

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Details

Laubacher StraBe 2,
Berlin, 14197
Germany
+49 17679851926
kinjalmore2015@gmail.com

NATIONALITY

Indian

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

10/31/1992

india

Links

LinkedIn

Github

Skills

PostgreSOL

Git
JavaScript
NodeJS
ReactJS
mysql
AWS
Docker
MongoDB
MySQL

Profile

Over 7+ years of extensive experience in web-based applications. Worked mainly with application software analysis, design, development, and testing of web (all the phases of SDLC and quality assurance/testing). Skilled in NodeJS, ExpressJS, TypeScript, Micro-Services, Angular, RXJS, ReactJS, REDUX and RESTAPI. To seek a challenging position in a company to a motivating and vibrant work environment. Currently located in berlin Germany.

Employment History

Fullstack Developer, Gamigo Group AG, Berlin, Berlin

FEBRUARY 2023 - PRESENT

- development and deployment of multiple web applications using Angular 15, RxJS, Material Design, and NgRx.
- Collaborated with the team to design and implement new user interfaces, improving the user experience by 25%.
- write unit test cases in chai and mocha.

Backend Developer, DevDigital, Vadodara, India

MARCH 2021 - PRESENT

- Expertise in modern web architecture using various advanced JavaScript
 frameworks and libraries like NodeJS, ReactJS/Redux, bootstrap, material UI,
 ES7, ES6, ES5, and Typescript features for handling asynchronous data requests.
- Expertise in MERN (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, and NodeJS) stack applications.
- Worked on AWS large project using AWS Cognito, Lambda, API gateway, node back-end, MySQL, store procedure React/Redux front-end.
- Worked on AWS RDS database and EC2 instance integration
- Worked on complex 3-tier architecture and complex system form.
- Expertise using React Component, Reducers, and Actions to implement MVC and Redux architecture and having experience with Middleware.
- Working as a Technical Lead involves client handling, and joining the scrum calls and client meetings.
- NodeJS Deploy on AWS CDK by using the Docker container
- Integrated Stripe and RazorPay payment gateway
- Webhook and RESTAPI integration.

Backend Developer, Corigami Technologies pvt ltd, Vadodara

JANUARY 2019 - MARCH 2021

- RESTful API design and development using NodeJS, ExpressJS, and microservices.
- Extensively used Promises, async, await and event emitter in NodeJS to avoid callbacks and more readable code.
- Build great online seamless user experience using modern frameworks and libraries.
- Good understanding of Document Object Model (DOM), DOM Funtion,
 ReactJS Componant, Redux
- manage different API responses in a single one by using micro-services.

- Responsible for writing server-side web application logic, developing back-end components, connecting the application with the other (often third-party) web services, and supporting the front-end developers by integrating their work with the application.
- Sound Understanding and good experience with Object Oriented Concepts,
 Object Oriented JavaScript, Object Oriented Design and Implementation
- Architected and lead the transition from monolith to a cloud-based microservice architecture on AWS

Backend Developer, www.purchasekaro.com, Vadodara

JULY 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

- worked on making micro-services and third party API integration like hotel booking api, bus booking api,flight booking api,payment gateway api, domestic money transfer api.
- experience with **SQL** schema design, **SOLID** principles, **REST API** design.
- Strong grip on api creation and api integration.
- Expertise in developing and updating web pages quickly using JavaScript/Typescript, React, Redux, HTML/CSS
- worked on B2B, B2C portals
- wrote non blocking code using numerous advanced techniques and strategies such as a multi threading & JavaScript dependency management.

Web Developer, Myrestica Technologies PVT LTD, Vadodara

JULY 2015 - JUNE 2017

- Developing and making code more modular by using the Model View Control (MVC)
- Database designing for regular and e-commerce portals
- Strong grip on object-oriented programming
- Provide development support to the government client and enable design, development, and implementation of complex Disability System
- Excellent communication skills with ability to articulate concepts and ideas through verbal, written and illustrative means
- Strong initiative and motivated to take ownership
- Meticulous attention to detail
- Intermediate to advanced knowledge of web technologies and browsers
- Excellent understanding of CSS, HTML & Javascript

Education

Bachelor's in Information Technology, University of Gujrat, Vadodara

JULY 2010 - JUNE 2014

Backend Technology

• NodeJS, ReactJs, ExpressJS, AWS Services.

Frontend Technology

- Javascript, ES6, ES7
- ReactJs, VueJS.

Database:

• MYSQL, SQL. PostgreSQL

• Mongo DB, PouchDB, CouchDB.

Other Tool

- AWS services (Lambda, S3 bucket, Cloud Watch, Users, CDK, SDK, SAM CLI, Cloud Formation, Cloud Front, RDS, API gateway, Secret Manager, EC2 instance, Cognito User).
- Git, Jira, bitbucket.Worked on AWS project created API using AWS lambda and API gateway
- Postman, Docker, and ITPoker for time estimation

About Me

I am a very quick learner person. I keenly believe in updating my skills constantly. I am a nature-loving person and I love visiting beautiful places. I enjoy listening to soft music and reading in my free time.